<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beyond the Obvious</title>
    <link>https://hugsch.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Beyond the Obvious</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugsch.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to create a test files?</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/test_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/test_files/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need a test video or test image with a specific resolution, duration or framerate and specific content, e.g. gradient color, TV test image, counter or time code.
1. Generate test video with ffmpeg FFMPEG is a command line tool for handling (decode, encode, convert, &amp;hellip;) video and audio files. It is used by many commercial and free software products, including Blender. The core is the FFMPEG program, together with a video &amp;amp; audio player (FFPLAY) and a stream analyzer (FFPROBE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time code</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/time_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/time_code/</guid>
      <description>Every video editor has some kind of timeline. When a clip starts or ends is stored in a so called time code. Blender keeps track of several time codes. You can find some (but not all) of them, in the sidebar under the Time panel (see figure 1).
As the name implies, the timeline represents time (seconds). But, because the unit of a video clip (or strip in Blender talk) is one frame, the timeline is sometimes labeled in frames or a combination of time and frames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio volume slider</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/audio_volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/audio_volume/</guid>
      <description>Every program that works with audio has some sort of volume slider. And, they all have different meanings! In Blender, you can find it as a Property of the Audio Strip. It is a number between 0 and 100. A value &amp;gt; 1 will amplify the sound; a value &amp;lt; 1 will decrease the sound level. Simple, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But how loud is a volume level of 0.5? Is it half as loud as 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script Editor</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/script_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/script_editor/</guid>
      <description>Blender has a dedicated workspace &amp;ldquo;Scripting&amp;rdquo; with 7 windows (areas): the Text Editor (middle area), the Info editor (left bottom), the Python console (left middle) and the 3D Viewport (left top). At the right you find the Properties window (bottom) and two versions of the outliner (top); see fig. 1.
Fig 1. The scripting workspace (2.92 in 2021)
You can use the built-in text editor to write and test your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFMPEG useful commands</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/ffmpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/ffmpeg/</guid>
      <description>FFMPEG is a command line tool for handling (decode, encode, convert, &amp;hellip;) video and audio files. It is used by many commercial and free software products, including Blender. The core is the FFMPEG program, together with a video &amp;amp; audio player (FFPLAY) and a stream analyzer (FFPROBE).
1. Generate testfiles Sometimes you need a test video or test image with a specific resolution, duration or framerate. You can first try with ffplay to view the test video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color Picker</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/color_picker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/posts/color_picker/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that Blender has five different color pickers? No? You can choose between them in the Preferences panel (Edit » Preferences » Interface). They look rather intuitive to use (see Figure 1). But even for this simple tool, several questions arise and trying to answer them will get you very fast into deep Blender space!  Why do we need 5 of them? Is it only a matter of preference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/index_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/index_old/</guid>
      <description>Look at these pages as the log book of an explorer, one who discovers unknown territory. Magnificent views but also sometimes -most of the time- harsh environment. Like so many others, I wanted to give Blender a try, a few years ago. So, I downloaded the program, opened it and then after a few hours closed it, not to reopen it for the next several months. It was not that I wasn’t thrilled: looking at a floating 3D-cube that I could actually move and rotate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to expect?</title>
      <link>https://hugsch.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugsch.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Blender is a free and open source 3D creation suite. It supports the entire 3D pipeline: modeling, rigging, animation, simulation, rendering, compositing and motion tracking, video editing and 2D animation. It’s an amazing program, with a great community and a lot - I really mean a lot - of information and tutorials. So why, another documention website?
Look at these pages as the log book of an explorer, one who discovers unknown territory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
